unsw.edu.au 2013-06-30

# Privacy Policy | The University of New South Wales

Personal information collected at the University of New South Wales ("UNSW") through UNSW websites is handled in accordance with the _Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998 (NSW)_ ("the Act"). This UNSW Websites Privacy Statement describes the ways in which UNSW deals with personal information and other data collected through UNSW websites.

 **What is Personal Information?**

Personal Information is defined in the Act as being information or an opinion about an individual whose identity is apparent or can reasonably be ascertained from that information or opinion. Personal Information includes, for example, names, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses, dates of birth and passport numbers.

There are circumstances in which, under the Act, information about an individual is not considered to be Personal Information, including:

  * when it relates to a person who has been dead for more than 30 years; and
  * when it is contained in a publicly available publication.

 **Collection of Personal Information**

 **Personal Information provided by you**

UNSW has a number of privacy statements setting out how personal information is handled by the University. These include the [Student Privacy Code of Practice](https://my.unsw.edu.au/student/privacy.html), the [Human Resources Privacy Statement](http://www.hr.unsw.edu.au/employee/privacy.html) and other statements or policies that UNSW may approve from time to time.

UNSW provides feedback facilities on its websites to allow users to provide input into the future development of its websites and comment on the provision of services. Users must provide UNSW with a name and email address for the purpose of receiving a reply to their feedback. This information will only be used for the purpose for which it was provided and your name and email address will not be added to any mailing list by UNSW.

Information that you disclose in online forums or other interactive media is considered by UNSW and the common law to be public information and may therefore not be subject to protection under the Act.

 **Automatic collection of personal information**

UNSW may collect personal information and other data from you through the use of a Cookie or other automated means including server logs. A Cookie is a packet of data that a website puts on your computer's hard disk to identify you as a visitor to that website. The information collected by UNSW through Cookies and other means may include: your server address; your domain name; your IP address; the date and time of your visit; the pages accessed and documents downloaded; the previous site visited; the type of browser you used. You may choose to disallow Cookies through your web browser settings.

 **Use and disclosure of Personal Information**

Personal information provided by you to UNSW will be used by UNSW for the primary purpose for which you provided it and for other secondary purposes directly related to that primary purpose. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices of web sites external to UNSW.

The information that is automatically collected during each visit to a UNSW website is aggregated by UNSW with similar logged information. This aggregated information may be published by UNSW in internal reports to assist UNSW identify patterns of website usage and to improve and maintain the service of UNSW websites and any services offered. Aggregated information does not identify individual users and does not include personal information.

UNSW will not otherwise disclose your personal information without your consent unless otherwise authorised by law. UNSW may disclose personal information to a third party if the disclosure is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to the life or health of you or another person.

Personal information collected through UNSW websites which is no longer required by UNSW and which need not be retained by law will be destroyed.

 **Access to your Personal Information**

You have a right to access your personal information held by UNSW. You can also request amendment to that information if you believe that it is incorrect or make complaints about the information handling practices of UNSW or breaches of your privacy by UNSW.

Access and amendment requests, complaints and other privacy enquiries should be directed to:

UNSW Privacy Officer  
Email: [privacy@unsw.edu.au](mailto:privacy@unsw.edu.au)  
Web: [www.privacy.unsw.edu.au](http://www.privacy.unsw.edu.au/)  
Telephone: (02) 9385 2860
